American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, Nov. 1, 1882; 10-1/2x7-1/2; Comegys, B. B. (Benjamin Bartis), 1819-1900
    T.L.S. 1p.and end. Resignation from Society.
  - Letter to secretary of the American philosophical society [J.P. Lesley], Dec. 7, 1882; 8x5; Trübner & Co.
    London, L. 1p.,end. Financial matter.
  - Letter to secretary of the American philosophical society [J.P. Lesley], Dec. 28, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Stillé, Alfred, 1813-1900
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Resignation from Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 3, 1883; 8x5; Wood, H. C. (Horatio C.), 1841-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Resignation from Society.
  - Report of the committee appointed to draw up a memorial to the senate and house of representatives [of the United States], February 2, 1883; 7 15/16" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 6 pp. D.S.: F[rederick] Fraley, Persifor Frazer, Thomas H. Findley. Opposing transfer of Coast Survey to the Navy Department.
  - Letter to Peter H. Leslie [sic], Feb. 11, 1883; Davis, William Morris, 1850-1934
    A.L.S. 1p. Presents books to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, March 21, 1883; 11x8-1/2; Packard, Butler & Partridge, co.
    Phila., L. 2p. Looking for business.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 21, 1883; 11x8-1/2; Packard, Butler & Partridge, co.
    Phila., Printed L.S.:D.A.Partridge. 1p. Business.
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, March 29, 1883; 6-1/2x4-1/2; May, Joseph
    A.L.S. 3p.,end. Resignation from Society.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 13, 1883; Ryder, John A. (John Adam), 1852-1895
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 24, 1883, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.,] A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting Sends sketch on Brazilian paleontology.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Nov. 22, 1883; 7x4-1/2; Thayer, M[artin] Russell, 1819-1906.
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. Resignation from Society.
  - Letter to [J.Peter Lesley ?], Nov. 26, 1883; 9-1/2x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Fragment of L. 2p. Enc.wanting. Concerning two manuscripts intended for the Proceedings. Refers to translation by [H.] Phillips.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Dec. 12, 1883; 11x8-1/2; Society of the United Brethren for Propagating the Gospel Among the Heathen
    Bethlehem, Pa., A.L.S.: Edmund [Alexander] de Schweinitz 5p. Enc. Asserts its ownership of the Zeisberger and Pyrlaeus manuscripts deposited in A.P.S. in 1819 by Heckewelder. Refers to Curators' report. Cf. Proceedings, v.21, pp.280, 284-6.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 2, 1884; 8x5, 3-1/2x6; Society of the United Brethren for Propagating the Gospel Among the Heathen
    Bethlehem, Pa., A.L.S.: E[dmund Alexander] de Schweinitz 1p. and envelope Directions for return of Zeisberger and Pyrlaeus manuscripts.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 7, 1884; 8x5, 3-1/2x6; Society of the United Brethren for Propagating the Gospel Among the Heathen
    Bethlehem, Pa., A.L.S.: Edmund [Alexander] de Schweinitz 2p., end., and envelope, end. Acknowledges receipt of Zeisberger and Pyrlaeus manuscripts. Cf. Proceedings, v.21, p.418.
  - Letter to the officers of the American philosophical society, Jan. 7, 1884; 8x5; Camac, William
    Woodvale, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Resignation from Society.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 17, 1884; 10-1/2x7-1/2; Townsend, H. T.
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning loan of R.H.Lee papers. Mentions J.S.Price.
  - Letter to librarian of the Kansas academy of science, Jan. 20, 1884, 1885; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., L.S.:J.P.Lesley. 1p.and end. List of publications being forwarded.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 24, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Flanders, Henry, 1826-1911
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. Declines membership in Society.
  - Letter to secretary of the American philosophical society [J.P. Lesley], Jan. 26, 1884; 8x5; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, A.L.S.:N.Murray. 2p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1884; 8x5; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, A.L.S.:N.Murray. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1884; 8x5; France. Ministère de l'agriculture, du commerce et des travaux publics.
    Paris, L.S.:R.Zeiller. 2p.,end. In French. Order for publications.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Feb. 8, 1884; 10x8; Lyman, D.
    Wash., D.C., L.S. 1p.,end. Requests copy of article by E.Y McCauley
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Feb. 9, 1884; 8x5; Winsor, Justin, 1831-1897
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 4p.,end. R.H.Lee papers are being returned.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Feb. 13, 1884; 5x3; Dawson, Henry B. (Henry Barton), 1821-1889
    New York, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Sending publication. Seeking to buy Society's publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Philadelphia, Feb. 18, 1884; 8x5-1/4; Middleton, Thomas C. (Thomas Cooke), 1842-1923
    Villanova, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the manuscript by Parras of his travels in Spain and South America, with some emphasis on the mission for the Guaranis Indians of Paraguay. Could not identify Parras.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Feb. 25, 1884; 8-1/2x5; Dawson, Henry B. (Henry Barton), 1821-1889
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.,and enc. Exchange of publications. Enclosure is an invoice for books.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Philadelphia, March 3, 1884; 8x5-1/4; Middleton, Thomas C. (Thomas Cooke), 1842-1923
    Villanova, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the manuscript by Parras of his travels in Spain and South America, with some emphasis on the missions fro the Guarains Indians of Paraguay. Could not identify Parras.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, March 18, 1884; 8-1/2x5; Dawson, Henry B. (Henry Barton), 1821-1889
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Angry letter. Concerning exchange of publications. His were not a donation. Has not received any from Society, as per agreement.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 22, 1884; 8x5-1/4; Middleton, Thomas C. (Thomas Cooke), 1842-1923
    Villanova, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the manuscript by Parras of his travels in Spain and South America, with some emphasis on the missions for the Guaranis Indians of Paraguay. Could not identify Parras.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 22, [1884]; 5x3; Dawson, Henry B. (Henry Barton), 1821-1889
    New York, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.and add. Exchange of publications. Has not received and from Society, as per agreement. Refers to Mary Lesley.
  - Letter to secretary the American philosophical society [J.P. Lesley], March 25, 1884; 8-1/2x5; Dawson, Henry B. (Henry Barton), 1821-1889
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.,end.and enc. Society's publications arrived, but without invoice. Willing to send additions to his publications. Enclosure is a bill of lading.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 17, 1884; 8x5; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    A.L.S.:W[illiam] Brooke Rawle. 2p.and end. Requests permission to keep Penn - Logan correspondence a while longer.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 29, 1884; 8x5; Wharton, Francis, 1820-1889
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Declines membership in Society.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 13, 1884; 9x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.L.S. 1p.,end....Enc.wanting..... Returns manuscript.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 15, 1884; 11x9; Verein für Vaterländische Naturkunde in Württemberg. Stuttgart. Jahreshefte
    Stuttgart, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:F[erdinand] Krauss. 1p.,end. In German. Order for publications.
  - Letter to Prof. E[dward] D[rinker] Cope, July 7, 1884; 8x5; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash., D.C., A.L.S. 1p....Enc.wanting.... Sends manuscript.
  - Letter to secretary of the American philosophical society [J.P. Lesley], July 18, 1884; 8x5; Im Thurn, Everard Ferdinand, Sir, 1852-
    Pomeroon, British Guiana, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Asking loan of works by T.Schultz on Arawak language. Mentioned are D.Brinton and H.Phillips.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 22, 1884; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Syle, Edward William
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning his election to membership in Society.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, July 22, [1884]; 5x3; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    A.L.on postal card S.with initial. 1p.and add. Concerning paintings of the Scaliger family. On same sheet is note from D.G.B[rinton] to [Henry Phillips], [July, 1884].
  - Note to [Henry Phillips], July, 1884; 5x3; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.N.on postal card S.with initials. 1p. Recommends placing paintings of the Scaliger family in Society's rooms. On same sheet as letter from [Henry] P[hillips] to D.G.Brinton, July 22, 1884.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 1, 1884; 5x3; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Phila., A.L.on postal card S.with rubber stamp. 1p.and add. Concerning map for article.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 1, 1884; 10-1/2x8-1/2; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L. 1p.,end. Mutilated. Request for publications.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, Aug. 8, 1884; 8x5; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    Uniontown, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his forthcoming memoir on the geology of Virginia. Mentions J.W. Powell(?).
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, Aug. 8, 1884; 8x5; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    Uniontown, Pa., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Discusses an additional memoir he has written on the geology of Virginia.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 9, [1884]; 3x5; St. Mary's Seminary and University (Baltimore, Md.)
    Baltimore, A.L.on postal card S.:A.Magnien,president. 1p.,end.and add. Can give no information about L.Girardin
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Aug. 11, 1884; 10x8; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning article on the Aruba language. Refers to E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.] P. Lesley, Aug. 12, 1884; 10x8; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash., D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Refers to his article on the Aruba language. Mentions E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 22, 1884; 10x8; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Wash.,D.C., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:James C[onstantine] Pilling. 1p.,end. No receipt received for publications sent to Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 29, 1884; 10x7-1/2; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Wash. D.C., T.L.S.:James C[onstantine] Pilling. 1p. and end...Enc.wanting.... Sends receipt. Concerning publications sent to Society.
  - Memorandum pertaining to the sending of Society publications to Dulau & co., Aug., 1884-1885; 8x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    London, D. 1p.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Sept. 3, 1884; 5x3; Macmillan & Co.
    London, L.on postal card. 1p.,end.and add., and enc. Concerning Society's order for publications. Enclosure is a parcel ticket for publications.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Sept. 6, 1884; 10x8; Brockway, C. B.
    Bloomsburg, Pa., A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.P.L[esley]....Enc.wanting.... Offers paper on meteorological observations. Refers to Baron von Humboldt.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], Sept. 9, 1884; 8-1/2x6; E. Steiger & Co.
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end. Order for publications.
  - Letter to C.B. Brockway, Bloomsburg, Pa., Sept. 13, 1884; 11x8-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning the presentation of his paper to the Society. On same sheet is letter from C.B. Brockway to J.P.Lesley, April 27, 1885.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Sept. 15, 1884; 10x8; Brockway, C. B.
    Bloomsburg, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Permission to use his article on meteorological observations.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Sept. 24, 1884; 5x3; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Hazelton, Pa., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.and add. Concerning financial matter. Plate for his paper on mammals.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 27, 1884; 11x8-1/2; Association of Engineering Societies (U.S.)
    St. Louis, Mo., A.L.S.: J[ohn] B[utler] Johnson. 1p.,end. Exchange of Publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 1, 1884; 9x5-1/2; Little, Brown and Company
    Boston, A.L.S.:D.Jefferson. 1p.,end. Order for publications.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Oct. 3, [1884]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Trübner & Co.
    [London], L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Asking about publication.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], Oct. 8, 1884; 8x5; France. L'institut national
    Paris, A.L.S.:E[ugène-Amédée] Tardieu. 1p.,end. In French. Order for publication.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Oct. 9, 1884; 5x3; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning use of Society's plate in the American naturalist.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 15, 1884; 9x5-1/2; Holmes, E. S.
    Grand Rapids, Mich., A.L.S. 1P., end. Received wrong publication. Refers to sharks.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Oct. 15, 1884; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Macmillan & Co.
    London, L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [J.P. Lesley], Oct. 17, 1884; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. Discusses his pamphlet, formally anonymous, on the Coast and geodetic survey.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [J.P. Lesley], Oct. 17, 1884; 5x3; Townsend, Charles Henry Tyler, 1863-
    Constantine, Mich., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.and add. Asking for article by J.LeConte and G.Horn.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, October 21, 1884; Stevenson, J. J., (John J.)
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, president of A.P.S., Oct. 26, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Accepts appointment to prepare obituary of R.E.Rogers.
  - Letter to Heliotype printing co., Boston, Oct. 28, 1884; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.L.S.:Henry Phillips. 2p.and end.,and env. Copy. Financial matter. Cost of reproductions
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 29, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Heliotype Printing Co.
    Boston, A.L.S.:S.D.Sargeant. 2p. Concerning financial matters.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 30, 1884; 5x3; Holmes, E. S.
    Grand Rapids, Mich., A.L. on postal card S. 1p.and add. Returned publication to Society.
  - Letter to publishing committee of A.P.S., Oct. 31, 1884; 9x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 1p.,end. Order for publications.
  - Letter to [J.P.] Lesley, Nov. 5, 1884; 9x6; Mercantile Library of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: John Edmands, librarian. 2p.,end. Wishes to complete Society's publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [J.Peter Lesley], Nov. 5, 1884; 8x5; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:James C.Pilling. 1p.,end. Order for [D.G.] Brinton's article on Cakchiquel grammar.
  - Letter to publication committee of A.P.S., Nov. 6, 1884; 9x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 1p. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 7, 1884; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Scribner's Sons, Charles
    New York, L. 1p.,end. Order for publications. Mentioned is paper by T.Crane on folk-lore.
  - Letter to L.W.Morris & son, New York, Nov. 11, 1884; 9x6; Cook, H.
    Phila., L. 1p.,end. Concerning Dulau's box.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Nov. 17, 1884; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Death of E.K.Price. Mentions J.S. Price.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1884; 10-1/2x8-1/2; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L. 1p.,end.,and end. Mutilated. Order for publications.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, Nov. 25, 1884; 10x8; Thompson, Robert Ellis, 1844-1924
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning a book by von Hammer[?].
  - Letter to G.W.Wheatley & co., Liverpool, Nov. 28, 1884; 10x8; London & North Western Railway Society
    Liverpool, L. 1p.,end. Concerning Dulau's box.
  - Report of committee of... upon paper signed "Time is Money" offered for the Megellanic premium, December 10, 1884; 5" x 8"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. P[liny] E. Chase, E. Otis Kendall. Paper not recommended for Magellanic premium.
  - Letter to Heliotype printing co., Boston, Dec. 12, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Dr.of L.S.:Henry Phillips, secretary. 2p. Concerning cost of reproductions.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 13, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Heliotype Printing Co.
    Boston, L. 1p. Concerning financial matter.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S. [Frederick Fraley], Dec. 17, 1884; 8x5; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    Hartford, Conn., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Asking whether J.Priestley's portrait was ordered by the Society from G.Stuart.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred the communication signed "Arcturus", December 18, 1884; 4 15/16" x 8 1/16"; American Philosophical Society
    offered for the Magellanic premium, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: F. A. Genth, Charles M.Cresson, Persifor Frazer. Magellanic award not recommended.
  - Letter to publishing committee of the A.P.S., Dec. 22, 1884; 8x5; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 1p.,end.,and end. Order for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society; Boston, Dec. 24, 1884; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Heliotype Printing Co.
    L. 1p.,end. Thanks for order.
  - Report of... recommending the publication of the Lenapé Dictionary of [David] Zeisberger, December 30, 1884; 8 1/8" x 10 1/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton and three others. Cost of preparation of the MS. not to exceed $300.
  - List of members residing within ten miles of the hall, Jan. 1, 1885; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 4p.,end.
  - Letter to F.P. Lesley(sic), Jan. 1, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Societas pro Fauna et Flora Fennica
    Helingfors, Finland, A.L.S.:L.Bergroth. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Jan. 2, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [Phila.,]. A.L.S. 1p.,end. Declines renomination as librarian of Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 3, 1885; 9-1/2x8; Elliot, S. Sowell
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 6, 1885; Gatschet, Albert S., (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Jan. 10, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Offers article on the limulus to the Society.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, January 12, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Trübner & Co.
    London, L.on postal card. 1p.,end.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Jan. 14, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 14, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Heliotype Printing Co.
    Boston, L. 1p. Concerning order for printing.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 23, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S.:S[pencer] F[ullerton] Baird. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 25, 1885; 8x5; Holmes, E. S.
    Grand Rapids, Mich., A.L.S. 1p.and add., and end. Waiting for publication. Enclosure is a bill from Society.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 28, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his article on the limulus.
  - Letter to J[ohn] S[ergeant] Price, Jan. 28, 1885; 8x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning members of the Society who do not pay dues. Mentioned are J.Rothrock and J.B.Britton, among others.
  - Letter to J.P[eter] Lesley, Jan. 30, 1885; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Wash.,D.C., T.L.S.: James C.Pilling. 1p.,end. Order for publication. Refers to D.G. Brinton.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 31, 1885; 9x6; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:Edw[ard] J. Nolan. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 31, 1885; 9x6; Mercantile Library of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:John Edmands,Librarian. 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 31, 1885; 9-1/2x6; Hotchkiss, Jedediah, 1828-1899
    Staunton, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Asking for illustrations used by J.J. Stevenson. Refers to I.C.White.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 31, [1885?]; 7x4-1/2; Agassiz, Elizabeth Cabot Cary, 1822-1907
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p. Enc wanting. Sends dollar for publication.
  - Letter to [Thomas Sinclair & son;]., Jan., 1885?; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Wilder, Burt G. (Burt Green), 1841-1925
    T.L.S. 1p. Charges for printing and lettering. On same sheet as bill from Thomas Sinclair & son to B.G.Wilder, Jan.4,1885.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1883; Beehler, William Henry, 1848-1915
    A.L.S. 1p. Written on reverse of advertisement for "The Cruise of the Brooklyn".
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 3, 1885; 8-1/2x5; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, L.S.:N.Murray. 2p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 7, 1885; 8x5-1/2; M’Calla & Stavely
    Phila., Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.end. by D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton. Estimate for printing matter.
  - Memorandum pertaining to the publications of the Society which were sent to the University of Michigan, Feb. 9, 1885; 9x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.,end.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 10, 1885; 11x8-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Returns proof-sheet. Concerning publications. Authorizes him to destroy the casts(?) in the garret.
  - Letter to Breuker & Kessler, Feb. 10, 1885; 11x8-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Sends proof of paper, and map.
  - Letter to J[edediah] Hotchkiss, Staunton, Va., Feb. 11, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.Dr.of L.S.:Henry Phillips,secretary. 2p.,end.by D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, and add. Illustrations from J.Stevenson's paper will be sent after the paper is published in the Proceedings. Refers to J.P.Lesley.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 11, 1885; 8x5; Mallet, John William
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Says he is returning to the University of Virginia.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Feb. 12, 1885; 8x5; Paine, Robert Treat, 1803-1885
    Brookline, Mass., A.L.S. 2p.,end.and enc. Solar eclipses. Refers to S.C.Walker. Enclosure is a newspaper clipping on the eclipse of the sun of March 16, 1885.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 12, 1885; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning new members and other Socie business. Mentioned is J.Mallet, among others. FILM54-66 FRAME 192
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 12, 1885; 7-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., L.in 3rd P.S.:N.P.Scudder. 1p.,end. Acknowledges receipt of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 13, 1885; 2x3-1/2; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    A.L.on calling card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Introduces his assistant.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 13, 1885; 3x5; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S.:Edw[ard] J.Nolan. 1p.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 13, 1885; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Business of dues and other Society matters. Mentions J.Mallet.